# Santino Mantineo

# Full-Stack Developer

Argentina, Mendoza| +54 9 261 205 3982| <u>santinomantineo@gmail.com</u> Santino Mantineo [<u>www.linkedin.com/in/santino-mantineo-318231201</u>] -SantinoMantineo [<u>https://github.com/SantinoMantineo</u>]

### About Me

I have passion for using code as a tool for solving new problems. I'm a native Spanish speaker with an official C1 degree in English and I have experience working as a freelance fullstack developer, developing a real E-Commerce, also I played the role of project manager in a team of six developers. My expertise includes React, Redux, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Next JS and TypeScript. Besides Framer Motion, Tailwind, Styled Components, Figma and Photoshop.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **Software Engineer**

January 2024 – Present. Vetli · Seasonal

I am currently working for Vetli, a startup operating in Hong Kong and soon Europe, where I serve as a Software Engineer. Vetli is an application facilitating pet owners to schedule appointments and conduct online consultations with veterinarians. My role involves driving the technical aspects of the platform, ensuring seamless functionality and user experience.

# **Full Stack Developer**

Dec 2023 – January 2024.
Paid Freelance Project. "Tiendas Locales"

"Tiendas Locales" is a paid freelance project based on the idea of E-Commerce, which offers a way to connect a city of more than 15,000 people. I implemented secure payments, efficient databases, and real-time notifications. Additionally, I developed a post system and the full logic in payments, dashboard, posts, reviews, login, register, etc.

Some of the features applied in this project are JWT Auth, Third-party Authentication, Payment Gateway Integration, Combined Filters, Firebase, Email Notifications, Admin Dashboard, and Logical Deletion, Local Storage/Persistence, Reviews Translation, Socket.io.

# **TECH STACK:**

**Frontend**: React, Redux, Keyframes, Framer Motion.

Backend: Node.js, Express, Mercado Pago API, socket.io, JWT, Auth0, Firebase, nodemailer.

Databases: Sequelize, PostgreSQL

Programming Languages: JavaScript, CSS

Work Tools: Git, Slack.

# **PROJECTS**

Full Stack Web Developer - Lo Canjeamos?

oct. 2023 -nov. 2023

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Lo Canjeamos is a user-centric platform addressing rising e-commerce prices in Latin America. The visually engaging interface boasts a dynamic carousel, comprehensive product listings, and an intuitive navigation system. Users can swap new or pre-loved items, create profiles, and connect with potential matches.

Some of the features applied in this project are JWT Auth, Third-party Authentication, Payment Gateway Integration, Combined Filters, Cloudinary, Email Notifications, Admin Dashboard, and Logical Deletion, Local Storage/Persistence, Reviews Translation. I performed the project manager role, guiding a team of six. I implemented SCRUM methodologies to ensure efficient project management.

Front: <React, Redux>

Back: <Node Js.

Express>

Base de datos: PostgreSQL, Sequelize.

<github.com/SantinoMantineo/Lo-Canjeamos>

### Full Stack Web Developer - Dog's Club

sept. 2023 -oct. 2023

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

Users can create their ideal virtual dogs by customizing breeds, colors, and personalities. The platform provides robust search and filter options for effortless exploration of the diverse canine universe. Each virtual dog card offers in-depth information about the furry companion, allowing users to delve into unique traits.

Front: <React, Redux> Back: <Node Js, Express>

Base de datos: PostgreSQL, Sequelize. <github.com/SantinoMantineo/PI-Dogs-main>

### Full Stack Web Developer - Rick & Morty Web

aug. 2023 -sept. 2023

Academic Experience. Henry Bootcamp

A passion project born from my journey through each bootcamp's module. You can create and add Favorites R&M characters.

Front: <React, Redux> Back: <Node Js, Express>

Base de datos: PostgreSQL, Sequelize.

<github.com/SantinoMantineo/Rick\_Morty\_Vite>

# Full Stack Web Developer - Ligth-Web

oct. 2022 -oct. 2022 Personal project

The place to discover the latest trends in lighting and transform your spaces with style.

Front: <HTML, CSS> <github.com/SantinoMantineo/Light-Web

### **EDUCATION**

- Full Stack Web Developer. Henry Bootcamp. +800 theoretical-practical course hours. (July 2023 November 2023).
- Universidad Siglo 21. Marketing and Digital Advertising. 2023

### **COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION**

- Instituto Amicana. Completed English Course (2013 2022) Graduated with Honors.
- High School Dr. José Vicente Zapata. Bachelor in Audiovisual Arts with a Specialization in Audiovisual Production.

### **LANGUAGES**

- Spanish: Native.
- English C1.
- French Basic